Guide to the Kaufman / Eskowitz Family Papers, 1896-2008 MS 0788
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Kaufman/Eskowitz Family Papers
1896-2008
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Eskowitz, Sheryl
MS 0788
4 Linear Feet 6 boxes
The collection consists of six boxes containing immigration materials, correspondence, marriage records, directories, programs, newsletters, news clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, and memorabilia spanning the years 1896 to 2008.
Biographical / Historical
Lillian Weinberg was born in 1896 in Houston to Philip and Ida Weinberg. Benjamin Kaufman was born in Russia in 1894 and immigrated to the United States in 1912. Lillian and Benjamin married in 1921. The couple had two children, Raymond and Inez. Inez Kaufman was born on October 15, 1929. She grew up in Houston and graduated from Reagan High School. She attended University of Texas at Austin.
Maurice Eskowitz was born in Galveston to Harry and Adele Eskowitz in 1925 and the family moved to Houston when Maurice was ten years old. He graduated from Jefferson Davis High School in 1943 and attended the University of Houston until joining the Army the following year. Maurice spent two years in the Army, serving in the Philippines and Korea before being discharged in May 1946. After returning, he continued his education at UH, graduating in 1950.
Inez married Maurice Eskowitz in 1952. The couple had three children, Sheryl, Bruce, and Barbara. Maurice died July 4, 2013, and Inez died March 6, 2019. Both are buried at Beth Yeshurun Cemetery on Post Oak.
Scope and Contents
Six boxes containing immigration materials, correspondence, marriage records, directories, programs, newsletters, news clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, and memorabilia document the lives of members of the Kaufman and Eskowitz families from 1896 to 2008.
Forms part of the South Texas Jewish Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Sheryl Eskowitz, August 2018.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in four series as follows:
Series I: Benjamin and Lillian (Weinberg) Kaufman Series II: Sheryl Eskowitz Series III: Maurice and Inez (Kaufman) Eskowitz Series IV: Oversize
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Jews and Jewish life; Social life and customs
Document Types
photographs; pamphlets; Programs (Publications); personal correspondence; Records (documents)
Subjects (Persons)
Eskowitz, Sheryl
- Series I: Benjamin and Lillian (Weinberg) Kaufman
  - Benjamin and Lillian Kaufman Immigration Materials, 1896-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin and Lillian Kaufman Ketubah and Marriage License, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Maurice Eskowitz Certificates, 1945-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Maurice Eskowitz News Clippings, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Maurice Eskowitz Photographs, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Maurice Eskowitz Hotel Information, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Benjamin Kaufman Memorial Materials, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Deborah Weinberg Memorial Materials, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter to Lillian Kaufman, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lillian Kaufman Memorial Materials, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ray Kaufman Memorial Materials, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Book by Robert Weiner, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sharon Goldstein News Clippings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: Sheryl Eskowitz
  - BBYO Programs, Directories, and Information, 1969-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - BBW Award, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - BBW Invitations and Programs, 1987-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - BBW Newsletters, 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Beth Israel Newsletters and Programs, 1988-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Shlenker News Clippings, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Shlenker School Activities, 1989-2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - JWI Meeting Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Shlenker Promotional Materials, 1990-1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Shlenker School Directories, 1990-2002 (Box 2)
  - Shlenker School Newsletters, 1990-2002 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Parent Guides, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - JWI Programs and Invitations, 1997-2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Shlenker School Annual Reports, 1998-2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - JWI Photographs, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - JWI News Clippings, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - BBYO Newsletters and Yearbook, 2001-2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - BBYO News Clippings, 2005-2014 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - BBYO - Jewish Herald Voice Scrapbook, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Shlenker Class Photograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - BBW News Clippings, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - BBYO Photographs, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series III: Maurice and Inez (Kaufman) Eskowitz
  - Inez Kaufman Photographs, 1935-1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Religious School Documents, 1937-1945 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Inez Programs and Invitations, 1939-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Inez Kaufman News Clippings, 1943-1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - High School Club Documents, 1944-1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Magazines and Newsletter, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Essays and Speech, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - High School Graduation Documents, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Inez Sorority Documents, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - University of Texas Documents, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Post Cards, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Engagement Letter, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Menus, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Series IV: Oversize
  - Phillip Weinberg Citizenship Document, 1906 (Box 6)
  - Maurice Eskowitz High School Diploma, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Reagan High School Yearbooks, 1944-1946 (Box 5)
  - University of Houston Yearbooks, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Wedding Scrapbook, 1952 (Box 6)
  - The Three Pillars: A Book For Jewish Women, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Memorial Book For Deborah Weinberg, 1962 (Box 6)
  - B'nai Brith Girls Progressive Dinner Guide, 1971 (Box 6)
  - B'nai Brith Women Ceremonial Gavel, 1971 (Box 6)
  - B'nai Brith Youth Shirt, 1978 (Box 6)
  - B'nai Brith Women Decorative Shoe, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Book Bank Collection Bag, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Jewish Women International Box, n.d. (Box 6)
  - B'nai Brith Women Shirt, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Sheryl Eskowitz Embroidered Shirt, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Lillian Weinberg Bridal Book, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Cassette Tape Reel, n.d. (Box 6)